Subahu Paul

Queens, NY | subahupaul0016@gmail.com | (347) 901-7944 | https://spaul0016.github.io/spaul/

Summary

Highly passionate and skilled professional with a Bachelor of Technology in Computer Information Systems and 9 months of IT internship and 1.5 years of experience in aviation. Areas of focus and interest include information systems, and cybersecurity. Seeking to apply my knowledge and work experience to fill your open position.

Skills

Operating Systems: Linux/Unix, Windows, Mac OS

Programming/Scripting Languages: Java, Bash/Shell, Python, SQL, MySQL

Framework/Technologies: Agile, Active Directory, Virtual Machines, Git, Visual Studio, Eclipse, Cisco Packet Tracer,

Selenium, Cucumber, Maven, TestNG, Jira, SDLC, STLC, MS Office

Education

Bachelor of Technology: Computer Information Systems

New York City College of Technology

GPA: 3.10/4.00 Brooklyn, NY

Relevant Coursework: Project Management, Database Systems, Task Automation in System Admin, Virtualization, Operating Systems, Networking, Systems Operation, Advanced Security Technologies

Experience

Turnaround Coordinator, Swissport USA Inc | (JFK Airport) Queens, NY

10/2024 - Present

- Coordinate all pre and post-departure activities, including fueling, catering, baggage, and cargo loading/unloading and maintenance checks, ensuring on-time departure.
- Manage baggage room operations by supervising loading procedure, checking baggage tags, and resolving any issues to prevent delay or lost baggage.
- Conduct thorough safety inspections and communicated real-time updates with ground and cabin crews, enhancing passenger and crew safety and minimizing operational disruptions.
- Collaborate closely with ramp agents, gate agents, and other team members to optimize turnaround processes, reducing ground time.

Turnaround Coordinator, Jet Way Aviation LLC | (JFK Airport) Queens, NY

11/2023 - Present

- Oversee ground operations to ensure efficient aircraft loading/unloading, baggage handling, and adherence to safety protocols, resulting in on-time departures and arrivals.
- Effectively manage ground service equipment, allocate manpower, and coordinate with other departments to optimize resources, minimize delays, and maintain a smooth workflow during the operational period.
- Enforce and monitor strict safety standards, conduct regular inspections, and promptly report incidents, maintain a safe environment to meet the airline and TSA guidelines.
- Work as part of a team to coordinate ramp activities, communicating with other ramp agents, flight crews, and other ground staff to ensure a high standard of service.

Customer Service Agent, Jet Way Aviation LLC | (JFK Airport) Queens, NY

02/2023 - 10/2023

- Checked passengers in for their flights while verifying their passports, visas and issued boarding passes.
- Assisted passengers with their baggage, including weighing, tagging, and checking it in, and coordinating any special handling requirements.
- Coordinated with other airport departments, such as TSA, ground handling, and maintenance, to ensure smooth operations and on-time departures for flights.

IT Intern, CWA Local 1180 | New York, NY

09/2021 - 06/2022

- Received phone calls and emails from users, and members and assisted them with their information technology
 questions and problems.
- Under supervision performed service functions in installing, maintaining, troubleshooting, or replacing computer hardware, software, and network components.
- Performed administrative tasks including maintenance logs of computer use, production of reports management and efficiently tracking work orders in the database.

Project

Enterprise Network Infrastructure:

- Collaborated with an IT admin to establish an efficient enterprise network.
- Used multiple networking tools such as routers, switches, servers, workstations to optimize network performance.
- Demonstrated proficiency in networking design and troubleshooting using Cisco Packet Tracer.

Tool: Cisco Packet Tracer